American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Native American Languages. 1882-1958 Mss.497.3.B63c
American Philosophical Society
- Sisiatl (Seechelt)
  - Sisialt vocabulary, ca.1885; AMs, 14p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    In Seechelt-German. 871 lexical items arranged topically with German equivalents.
    Freeman and Smith 3232
- Seneca
  - Seneca ... recorded from Ezechiel Hill, a Seneca of Grand River Reserve, Ontario, 1950; AMs, 39p. Photo.; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
    Verb forms, terms of relationship, numerals. Check list of vocabularies found appended to Jacques Cartier's first and second voyages.
    Freeman and Smith 3458
  - Seneca and other notes, 1947; AMs, 122L. and 37L.; Harris, Zellig S., (Zellig Sabbettai), 1909-
    Texts with interlinear translations.
    Freeman and Smith 3463
  - Seneca texts and additional external forms, 1946; AMs, 20L., 61L., and 5 records.; Harris, Zellig S., (Zellig Sabbettai), 1909-
    Freeman and Smith 3464
    Cf. No. 3463
- Shasta
  - The Shasta language, 1928-1930; TMs, 254L.; Angulo, Jaime de and Lucy S. Freeland
    Grammar and illustrative text with interlinear and free translations and notes. Author discusses language in terms of how ideas are expressed. Intended to parallel the authors discussion of Achumawi (1930). Also a carbon copy (244L.) lacking free translation.
    Freeman and Smith 3641
  - Shasta texts, 1908-1910; AMs, 8 notebooks, ca. 315p.; Dixon, Roland Burrage, 1875-1934
    Texts with interlinear translation. These are, in part, revised in No. 3644.
    Freeman and Smith 3643
  - Shasta texts ...; ed. and rev. by Lucy S. Freeland, 1908; 1927; TMs, 221L.; Dixon, Roland Burrage, 1875-1934
    Texts with interlinear and free translations. Folkloristic texts collected by Dixon see No. 3643 and checked with the informants of Jaime de Angulo and Freeland.
    Freeman and Smith 3644
  - Sample of Shasta, 1928; TMs, 1L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    48 forms based on a verb meaning to peel; marginal note of Edward Sapir.
    Freeman and Smith 3640
  - Knomihu vocabulary, obtained at Selma, Oregon, n.d.; 1928; AMs, 4L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    In English-Shasta. 49 items. Note of Edward Sapir.
    Freeman and Smith 3639
- Shuswap
  - Shuswap vocabulary, 1900; AMs, 15L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    900 forms arranged by categories such as tribal names, parts of the body, etc.
    Freeman and Smith 3673
  - Shuswap words, 1908; AMs, 12p. 5L. ca. 420 forms arranged by categories.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Freeman and Smith 3674
- Sinkyone
  - Sinkyone field notes, 1903-1908; AMs, 4 notebooks.; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928
    Contains lexical items with translations; also texts with interlinear translations. Lengthy notes in English on house types for Sinkyone of north and south in Humboldt County.
    Freeman and Smith 3675
- Southern Paiute
  - Ute and Kaibab Paiute linguistic material, 1909-1910, 1916, n.d.; AMs, 5 notebooks of ca. 150p. each and 55L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Notebooks include: paradigms, grammatical notes and texts for Uncompahgre and Uintah Ute and for Kaibab Paiute; lists of kinship terms from Thompson River (Salish), Nootka, Nass River (Tsimshian), Kutenai, Uintah Ute, Yurok, and Kaibab Paiute.
    Freeman and Smith 4766
    Donor, Sapir family, May 1972.
- Squamish
  - Squamish vocabulary, ca. 1890; AMs, 66L. 20p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    In Squamish-German. Part translated into German. May be from field work ca. 1885.
    Freeman and Smith 3697
- Takelma
  - Takelma linguistic material and songs, 1903-1904, 1906; AMs, 5 notebooks of ca. 120p. each, 6L. sheet music, 10L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939, coll.
    The notebooks contain myth texts with English translations, medicine formulas, etc. (published as Sapir, 1909) as well as paradigms and other grammatical notes. Sheet music contains transcriptions of four Takelma songs and one each for Chasta Costa, Shasta, and Chinook Jargon. Remaining leaves are vocabulary notes made by H. H. St. Clair. Informant: Francis Johnson.
    Freeman and Smith 4803
- Taos (Tiwa dialect)
  - A sketch of the Taos language, 1924-1930; AMs, 76L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Article considers morphology and semasiology (according to de Angulo and Freeland 1830). Three letters from literate informant, all with interlinear and free translation and notes.
    Freeman and Smith 3724
  - Taos texts and grammatical notes, n.d.; ca. 1924-1930; TMs, 68L.; Angulo, Jaime de and Lucy S. Freeland
    Contains four letters with literal and free translations and grammatical notes. 6 texts, most with free translations and notes. Note on revision of orthography.
    Freeman and Smith 3723
- Tarahumara
  - Tarahumara vocabulary, 1931; AMs, ca. 1,800 slips; Bennett, Wendell Clark, 1905-1953
    In Tarahumara-Spanish and English. Lexical file, organized both by grammatical categories and English alphabetical order.
    Freeman and Smith 3727
  - Tarahumara texts, 1931; TMs, and AMs, 105L.; Bennett, Wendell Clark, 1905-1953
    Tarahumara-Spanish and English. 13 texts with Spanish interlinear translans; 1 in English. Duplicate typed copies of 4 texts.
    Freeman and Smith 3726
  - Tarahumara materials, 1940; TMs and AMs, 192L.; Henry, Jules
    In Tarahumara-Spanish. Various Tarahumara materials relating to the work of the Consejo de Lenguas Indigenas. Includes vocabulary lists (Spanish-Tarahumara ) of 200 and 720 items; 1 Dictionario Tarahumara-Castellano of ca. 750 items; 7 texts with Spanish interlinear and from Cree translations. Also, printed Spanish reader, Plancarte (1939); mimeo. D., Spanish-Tarahumara newsletter; typed text (c.c.) in both languages, Significado Real della Educacion Socialista Discurso del Presidente Cardenas. Cartilla Tarahumara de Lectura by F. M. Plancarte contains photomechanical prints of housing, utensils, clothing, social customs. Vida Indigen also contains photomechanical prints.
    Freeman and Smith 3729
  - Tarahumara field notes, 1940; AMs, 3 notebooks and 11L.; Henry, Jules
    In Tarahumara-Spanish. Contains texts with some translations in Spanish; biographical material from informants; phonetically arranged lists of lexical items.
    Freeman and Smith 3728
- Tarascan
  - Tarascan vocabulary and notes, 1940; TMs and AMs, 1, 000 slips.; Lathrop, Maxwell D., Charles F. Hockett, and Adrian F. Leon
    In Tarascan Spanish. Lexical file; incomplete alphabetization.
    Freeman and Smith 3732
  - Tarascan ethnologic and linguistic notes, 1940; TMs, and AMs, 5 notebooks and 8L.; Swadesh, Frances, Adrian F. Leon, and Pablo Velasquez
    In Tarascan, English, and Spanish. Contains linguistic forms, terms for parents, vocabulary of 600 items, list of names of natural and cultural obiects. Interviews and material on land division and agriculture, both in Spanish.
    Freeman and Smith 3734
  - Words adopted from Spanish into Tarascan, 1939; TMs Cy, 4L.; Lathrop, Maxwell D.
    In Tarascan-Spanish-English. 75 items in parallel columns. Includes covering letter of Lathrop to Charles F. Hockett, Dec. 29, 1939, explaining the use of Spanish forms in Tarascan.
    Freeman and Smith 3731
  - Manual de eskritura en tB!po de mC3lde, n.d.; TMs with MS. Additions, 14L.; Unidentified
    In Spanish. A brief handbook for forming letters, with table of characters suitable for writing Tarascan.
    Freeman and Smith 3733
- Tehuelche
  - Patagonian Tehuelche myths, n.d.; TMs and AMs, 9L.; Wolf, J. G.
    In Tehuelche-English. 8 folkloristic texts with interlinear and free translations and notes. 4 texts in English from Spanish translations.
    Freeman and Smith 3735
- Tewa
  - Cochiti and San Juan Pueblo songs, 1957; TMs, 26L., 2 photos.; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Words, music, paraphrase of text, lists of ceremonial terms. Includes list of contents of Nos. 3734 and 3740; describes methods. Phonologic chart for Cochiti Keresan and Tewa-Tanoan.
    Freeman and Smith 3739
    Donor, Gertrude P. Kurath, 1957. Cf. Nos. 3734 and 3740.
  - Tewa word list, 1915; AMs, 2 slips.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    22 forms with English equivalents.
    Freeman and Smith 3743
- Tillamook
  - Tillamook and Siletz folkloristic texts, 1900; AMs, 54L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Texts with interlinear translation, pencil corrections. Copies of texts obtained in 1890.
    Freeman and Smith 3745
    Cf. Boas (1898) and No. 30 (S4.1)
  - Miscellaneous items on Tillamook, 1890; AMs, 8L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Contents of materials on Tillamook, Siletz, and Nehelim; also notes on Tillamook formations.
    Freeman and Smith 3744
  - Tillamook combined vocabulary, 1935; TMs with ms notes, 101L.; Edel, May M., (May Mandelbaum), 1909-1964
    Combines materials recorded by Boas, Melville Jacobs, and May Edel. Typescript with extensive handwritten corrections.
    Freeman and Smith 3748
- Tlingit
  - Tlingit and Haida word list, 1900-1901; AMs, 2 notebooks. 90p.; Swanton, John Reed, 1873-1958
    Field notes taken at Sitka and Wrangell for Tlingit; Howkan, Klinkwan, and Kassan, Alaska, for Masset-Haida.
    Freeman and Smith 3763
    Cf. Swanton (1911b).
  - Chilcat vocabulary, 1914; AMs, 4L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Notes taken from Louis Shotridge. 62 items.
    Freeman and Smith 3762
  - Recordings at Yakutat, Alaska, 1952; TMs, 30L.; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Table of contents and notes for No. 3755. Notes to reels 1-4. Contains songs, stories with some translations, mostly Tlingit. 3 Athabaskan songs.
    Freeman and Smith 3756
    Donor, Frederica de Laguna, 1959.
  - Tlingit and Yakutat songs, 1954; TMs Cy, 62p.; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Table of Contents to Record 30. For supplemental data see No. 3753 and 3754.
    Freeman and Smith 3759
    Cf. Year Book APS for 1954:179
    Donor, Frederica de Laguna, 1959
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.4
  - Notes on songs recorded in 1954, TMs Cy, 128p.; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Notes to and transcripts of reels 1-7 of No. 3758. This supplements No. 3759.
    Freeman and Smith 3754
    Donor, Frederica de Laguna, 1954
  - Classification of all Yakutat-Tlingit songs recorded in 1952 and 1954, TMs, 10p.; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Indexes songs of Nos. 3755 and 3758 as Potlatch, Mourning, Sad, Walking, Dancing, Peace, Sitting Down, Love, Miscellaneous, Shaman, Funny, and Children's Songs. For records, see Nos. 3755 and 3758. This supplements Nos. 3754, 3756 and 3759.
    Freeman and Smith 3753
    Donor, Frederica de Laguna, 1954.
  - Comparative Na-Dene dictionary, n.d.; AMs, 4 v. (ca. 500p. each.); Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Volumes 1, 3, and 4 are comparative Na-Dene with provision for various Athapascan languages and dialects, Waida, and Tlingit. Volume 2 is comparative Sino-Tibetan-Na-Dene with provision for entries in Sino-Tibetan languages, Athapascan, Haida, and Tlingit. Most pages in all volumes have only a few entries.
    Freeman and Smith 4851
- Tolowa
  - Tolowa field notes, 1902-1903; AMs, 18 notebooks.; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928
    Informants from Burnt Rock and Smith River Island, Calif. Lexical items, paradigms, songs, museum specimens, texts, historical narratives, ethnological data, names for material-culture objects.
    Freeman and Smith 3764
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 44-45
- Totonac
  - Los totonacos y su idioma, 1940; TMs part Cy, 27L.; McQuown, Norman A.
    In Spanish. Revision of Yale doctoral dissertation; includes introduction, explication of new Totonac alphabet, text, translation, and grammatical notes. Text, The Man and the Haawk, with English and Spanish translations.
    Freeman and Smith 3765
- Tsetsaut
  - Ts'ets'aut text and word list, 1894; AMs, 19L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Text with interlinear translation. Vocabulary obtained by Boas, Portland Canal, B.C.
    Freeman and Smith 3766
    Printed, Goddard (1924):34-35.
- Tsimshian
  - Process of change from matrilineal to patrilineal inheritance as illustrated in building, ownership, and transmission of hous, 1938; TMs, 19L.; Beynon, William, 1888-1958
    Discusses transition from the 1870s.
    Freeman and Smith 3774
  - Social organization of the Gitzaxtet tribes, 1915; TMs and AMs, 30p.; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
    Revision of formal paper. Lists Gitzaxtet Tsimshian houses and crests; typed copy with annotations of Edward Sapir. Covering letter of Barbeau to Franz Boas, Feb. 1, 1915, in which Barbeau discusses phonetics, social organization, and crests; disagrees with some of the Tate material upon which Boas based his Tsimshian mythology.
    Freeman and Smith 3768
  - Ethnographic and folkloristic texts of the Tsimshian, 1939; TMs, 544L.; Beynon, William, 1888-1958
    80 texts recorded in English. Copied from unpublished manuscript materials. Carbon copy has 10 additional texts.
    Freeman and Smith 3771
    Cf. No. 3777.
  - Indian legends of the North Pacific Coast of North America, 1974; TMs Cy, 600p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Legends in English from the German translation of Chinook Jargon, Kwakiutl, Tsimshian, and Shuswap. Translated by Deitrich Bertz from the original edition (see Boas 1895). Permission necessary for reproduction.
    Freeman and Smith 4854
    Donor, British Columbia Indian Language Project, Jan. 1975.
  - Tsimshian Lexicon, n.d.; Slip file, ca. 1, 000 slips.; Unidentified
    Reference numbers, apparently to field notes, unidentified.
    Freeman and Smith 3784
  - Tsimshian kinship terms, 1920-1939?; TMs and AMs, 33L.; Beynon, William, 1888-1958
    Kinship list of Boas filled in for man and woman as speaker by Beynon. Two narratives concerning tribal history. Text with interlinear narratives.
    Freeman and Smith 3776
  - Tsimshian word list, 1938; AMs, 53L.; Beynon, William, 1888-1958
    List of forms with German equivalents from Boas (1902); list of forms with English equivalents from Boas (1912), and from Beynon MS. List of forms from Beynon MS. Letters of William Beynon to Franz Boas, January 27 and February 12, 1939.
    Freeman and Smith 3777
  - English-Tsimshian dictionary, TMs Cy, 89L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Vocahulary of 2, 300 items, arranged alphabetically according to the English.
    Freeman and Smith 3778
    Cf. shorter list in Boas (1891)
  - Texts and word lists in Tsimshian, Ts'ets'aut, and Nisqa, 1894-1895; AMs, 4 notebooks (380p.); Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Original field notes. Most of texts have been published. Includes song texts with musicalscores. Some shorthand notes.
    Freeman and Smith 3779
    Printed, Boas (1902).
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 47-48
  - Tsimshian text and word list, 1893-1895; AMs, 1 notebook (10L.); Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Text with interlinear translation in German. Notebook copies vocabulary items secured at World's Columbian Exposition, 1893, Chicago.
    Freeman and Smith 3780
  - Tsimshian materials, 1940; TMs, part Cy, 111L. and 6 slips.; Susman, Amelia L.
    Contents: Phonemes. Connectives (morpholigical and syntactic relationships of connective suffixes). Grammatical and lexical notes. List of forms exemplifying statements made in Boas' Tsimshian sketch, in Handbook of American Indian Languages (1911). Nass forms and Tsimshian equivalents arranged in parallel columns. Text with interlinear translation. Based on field work of Susman, William Beynon, and on Boas article. Two letters of Susman to Boas, Oct. 18, 1940, and Nov. 5, 1940: experience with informants; linguistic analysis of ethnographic texts. Mentions Beynon, Viola Garfield, and Marius Barbeau.
    Freeman and Smith 3782
  - Tsimshian texts, 1906-1909; AMs, 49L.; Tate, Henry W.
    Texts with interlinear translation, 1 song with musical score. Apparently never published. Uses alphabet of Bishop Ridley. Two letters of Tate to Boas, March 25, 1906, and Dec. 18, 1909.
    Freeman and Smith 3783
  - Glosses to Boas' Tsimshian vocabulary, 1920; TMs and AMs Cy, 7L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Includes a 4p. lexical list, Tsimshian-English (glosses to Matheson text in No. 2372). Also "A Key to Tsimshian Sounds; tabular arrangement of consonants and vowels with use in Tsimshian word and translation." MS. additions in Sapir's hand.
    Freeman and Smith 3781
- Tualatin
  - Autobiography in Tfalati Kalapuya, n.d.; TMs, 53p.; Angulo, Jaime de and Lucy S. Freeland
    More than 300 numbered sentences. The first 28 have interlinear literal and free translations; the remainder have only free translations on separate pages. Informant: Louis Kenoy.
    Freeman and Smith 4856
  - Short grammatical analysis of Tfalati Kalapuya with appended comparison between Tfalati and Chinook jargon, TMs, 35p.; Angulo, Jaime de and Lucy S. Freeland
    Re: phonology and morphology. Includes: comparative texts; interlinear literal translations; free translations in English and French. Informant: Louis Kenoy.
    Freeman and Smith 4857
  - The Tfalati dialect of Kalapuya: texts, n.d.; TMs, 32p.; Angulo, Jaime de and Lucy S. Freeland
    Includes: numbered sentences in Tfalati; interlinear literal translations; free translations.
    Freeman and Smith 4858
- Tubatulabal
  - Tubatulabal text and grammatical sketch, ca.1932; TMs part Cy with ms additions, 20L.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986
    Text with interlinear translation and grammatical notes. Grammatical sketch with chart and contents. Letter of Voegelin to Boas, n.d., covering the MS.
    Freeman and Smith 3785
- Tunica
  - Tunica grammar, 1938-1940; TMs, 685L.; Haas, Mary R. (Mary Rosamond), 1910-, and Morris Swadesh
    Grammar, syntax, illustrative text. In 2 parts.
    Freeman and Smith 3790
    Printed, in shorter compass, as Haas (1940?).
  - Tunica texts, 1930-1938; TMs, 347L.; Haas, Mary R. (Mary Rosamond), 1910-, and Morris Swadesh
    Texts with free translation and notes. Contains introduction, phonetic key, and abbreviations; myths, tales, animal stories, historical and pseudo-historical narratives, personal narratives, miscellaneous ethnological data.
    Freeman and Smith 3791
    Printed as Haas (1950).
- Tuscarora
  - Notes to accompany Tuscarora recordings, 1948; 1949; TMs and AMs, 164p., 12p.; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Notes identify informants, describe techniques and difficulties of interviews. Recorded among Tuscaroras at the Niagara Falls Reserve in 1948. Texts of fluent Tuscaroras, attempts to translate these by Tuscaroras; anecdotes, Indian politics, genealogy and kinship terms, disease and magic, color perception, history and legend, and a reading of the Jefferson vocabulary. 1949 series: notes in regard to English translations, autobiographies, and thematic apperception tests.
    Freeman and Smith 3819
    Cf. Wallace (1949b).
    Donor, Anthony F. C. Wallace, grantee, 1949-1950.
  - Tuscarora texts and word lists, 1950; AMs, 118L.; Reyburn, William D.
    Interviews transcribed from recordings, No. 3818 texts (including several versions of Crossing the Ice) with translations, word lists, phoneme lists, paradigms.
    Freeman and Smith 3815
    Printed (text of Crossing the Ice), Wallace and Reyburn (1951).
- Tzeltal
  - Tseltal vocabulary, 1940; AMs,; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    In Tseltal-Spanish. List of 40 items.
    Freeman and Smith 3826
- Uto-Aztecan
  - Uto-Aztecan comparisons, 1913; Card file, 350 cards.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Lexical comparisons for 10-12 languages, mostly Uto-Aztecan and Nahuatl. Organized by English alphabetical order for the various phonetic units.
    Freeman and Smith 3832
    Printed, southernPaiute and Nahuatl comparisons only, Sapir (1914):379-425.
  - Azteco-Tanoan, 1936; AMs, 1L. Photo.; Whorf, Benjamin Lee, 1897-1941
    Diagram showing relationships and chronology of divergences.
    Freeman and Smith 3833
  - The Uto-Aztecan stock, n.d.; AMs Mimeo, 2L.; Whorf, Benjamin Lee, 1897-1941
    Presents relationships of Uto-Aztecan languages in outline form. Includes text and chart of Uto-Aztecan sound shifts.
    Freeman and Smith 3834
- Wailaki
  - Wailaki field notes, 1908; AMs, 10 notebooks.; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928
    Texts with interlinear translations; material on place names, with reference to enclosed MS. map. Deer hunting. Round Valley, California.
    Freeman and Smith 3835
    Printed (texts), Goddard (1923):77-135.
    Donor, A. L. Kroeber, for Department of Anthropology, University of California, 1946
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 44
- Wakashan
  - Wakashan comparative vocabulary, 1915-1952; TMs with MS. Additions, 30L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939, and Morris Swadesh
    A continuation of No. 3837:1-44, study compiled by Morris Swadesh on the basis of Sapir's Wakashan comparative notes No. 3838.
    Freeman and Smith 3838
  - Notes on Wakashan, 1910-1925; TMs and AMs, 47 slips.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Notes on various phonemes. Includes undated note from Sapir to Franz Boas.
    Freeman and Smith 3836
  - Wakashan comparative vocabulary, 1915-1951; TMs with MS. Additions, 45L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939, and Morris Swadesh
    Introduction: study compiled by Morris Swadesh on the basis of Sapir's Wakashan comparative notes, No. 3836. Continued in No. 3838.
    Freeman and Smith 3837
- Wasco
  - Wasco-Wishram Chinook linguistic material, 1905, 1930-1933, 1951, 1954; Cy and microfilm of AMs, ca. 22, 000 slips and 5 reels.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939, Walter Dyk, and Dell H. Hymes, comps.
    Vocabulary, paradigms, etc., collected at White Swan and Spearfish, Washington, and Celilo and Warm Springs, Oregon. Includes photocopy of a one-page letter from Michael Silverstein to Whitfield J. Bell, Jr., Sept. 29, 1972.
    Freeman and Smith 4892
- Whilkut
  - Whilkut field notes, 1907; AMs, 7 notebooks.; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928
    Notes taken at Redwood Creek. Texts with occasional interlinear translation. Subjects include names of tribes, village locations, etc.
    Freeman and Smith 3846
- Willapa
  - Willapa word lists, 1910-1924; AMs and TMs, 13L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    English Willapa lists, prepared from materials collected by James A. Teit, 1910.
    Freeman and Smith 3847
    Cf. Boas and Goddard (1924), where most of these items appear.
  - Notes to Willapa -- an Athabascan language, n.d., 1909?; AMs, 4L.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Comparative notes, based on a missing list of 139 Willapa items. Cf. Boas and Goddard (1924), note p. 39. List of museum specimens desired. Cf. correspondence in No. 30 (61), 1909.
    Freeman and Smith 3848
- Winnebago
  - The accentual system of Winnebago, 1938-1939; TMs Cy, 244L.; Susman, Amelia L.
    Based on field work in Wisconsin with Sam Blowsnake and wife. Contains letter from the author to Franz Boas, March 8, 1941, regarding symbols for printer; mentions William Beynon, Melville Jacobs, and Viola Garfield.
    Freeman and Smith 3901
    Printed (in shorter version), Susman (1943)
  - Winnebago materials, 1938-1939; AMs, 11 notebooks.; Susman, Amelia L.
    Texts with interlinear translation, word lists, ethnographical and linguistic notes. Several songs, texts. Contents.
    Freeman and Smith 3902
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 53-54
  - The Winnebago syllabary, 1939; TMs with MS. Additions, 37L.; Susman, Amelia L.
    Views syllabary as guide to Winnebago phonemics, comparing it with Algonquin syllabary. Intended for publication; letter from author to Franz Boas, Oct. 8, 1940, discusses publication plans and mentions work on Tsimshian. Mentions William Beynon and Paul Radin.
    Freeman and Smith 3903
- Wishram
  - Wishram place names and grammatical materials, 1920; AMs, 48p.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939 and Dr. Wolf
    Materials collected by Dr. Wolf: place names, stems, suffixes, together with evaluatory comments by Sapir. Letter of Sapir to Franz Boas, May 26, 1920, covers the notes.
    Freeman and Smith 3908
  - Wishram directional elements, 1930; AMs, 1L.; Dyk, Walter, 1899-1972
    List of directional terms and their usage; some miscellaneous items.